zip.ca 2013-06-02

# Zip.ca

We don't keep secrets. The purpose of our "Privacy Policy" is to make sure that you understand how we use your information, so you can rest assured that your privacy is protected. If you have questions about this policy, we're always here to help. 

### How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information

We at Zip.ca ("Zip", "we", "our", "us") respect and are committed to protecting our users ("you", "yourself", "your") privacy, and to making sure you know how we collect, use and disclose your personal information. By creating a free Zip.ca account, subscribing to a Zip.ca Mail plan or renting from a Zip.ca Kiosk, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We recommend that you take the time to read this Privacy Policy so that you understand how we handle and process personal information provided when you use Zip.ca. As we develop and expand our services, this Privacy Policy may also change. We will include a "last amended" date on the Policy as displayed on the website. We strongly encourage you to refer back to the Privacy Policy periodically. 

You can contact us if you have a question about our Privacy Policy or want to change or update your personal information at any time. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, "personal information" means information about an identifiable individual, but does not include the name, title or business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization. Zip.ca will not collect, use or disclose your personal information in a way that is incompatible with this Privacy Policy.

### How We Protect Your Personal Information 

Zip.ca makes all commercially reasonable efforts to protect your personal information from loss, unauthorized access, misuse or theft. We use a secure server (SSL) and encrypt all transmissions of personal information by you. We limit access to your account information with sign-in and password protection features. We encourage you to change your password regularly and to provide us with accurate information through the "My Account" page.

Only those Zip.ca employees who have a legitimate business purpose for accessing the personal information collected are authorized to do so. Unauthorized access to or use of personal information by an employee is prohibited and constitutes grounds for disciplinary action. In addition, our management systems are configured so as to block or restrict employee access from those without access privileges.

### When We Disclose Your Personal Information

Zip.ca will not sell, license, trade or rent your personal information to or with unaffiliated third parties. Zip.ca will not otherwise disclose your personal information except as described within this Privacy Policy.

Zip.ca may share certain information about you, including your contact and financial information, with our business partners where necessary or appropriate. In the event that certain services provided to you by or through Zip.ca or one of its business partners are to be provided to you by a substitute service provider, your information may be transferred to the substitute service provider provided that such substitute entity agrees to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy in effect at the time of performance of the services.

Zip.ca may also disclose personal information about account holders to a third party if a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order legally requires or authorizes us to do so, to enforce and protect the terms and conditions of our agreement(s) with you or the Terms of Use applicable to our website, or to collect on outstanding accounts.

Zip.ca also reserves the right to disclose and/or transfer personal information to a third party in the event of a proposed or actual purchase, sale, lease, merger, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal or financing of all or any portion of Zip.ca or of any of the business or assets or shares of Zip.ca, provided the third party represents that it will continue to use the information for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and in accordance with applicable privacy protection laws.

### Updating Your Personal Information

You may update or change your personal information anytime by visiting the "My Account" page

### Cookies and Web Logs

When you visit the Zip.ca website, cookies are placed on your hard drive. A cookie is a small piece of information that a website can store on your web browser and later retrieve. We use cookies to help us track items you select, to match your address and order, and to assist you in signing in to your account. We also use cookies to help us track use of our website, such as the number and frequency of visits to our pages and which parts of our website are visited. Most browsers will allow you to disable cookies. If your browser is set to disable cookies, you will not be able to sign in, create or update a rental list or use the "Account" section pages.

Zip.ca collects aggregate information concerning usage of the website through automatically logged information. Zip.ca does not use any personal information while generating this information, nor does it relate any of this information to an individual member or user.

### Statistical Analysis

We may collect your information, such as rental or purchase history, frequency of rental or purchasing behaviour, responses to marketing and promotional activities, website usage and other information. This information will be aggregated, so that it does not relate to any particular user. We may process and analyze this information, and/or combine it with other information, for the purposes of statistical analysis, identifying purchasing and/or rental trends, and other research. You cannot be identified by such aggregate data.

### Retention of Your Personal Information

We retain your personal information, including sign-in information, shipping information, rental history and financial information for the purposes described above, for such further periods as required by applicable laws or limitation periods and as necessary to allow us to guard against fraud and unauthorized abuse of further Zip.ca Mail free trials or other Zip.ca promotions. 

### Links to Third Party Sites

This website may offer links to other third party websites. You should be aware that operators of linked websites may also collect your personal information (including information generated through the use of cookies) when you link to their websites. Zip.ca is not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information, so it is important to familiarize yourself with the Privacy Policies of these websites before providing your personal information.

### Email for Marketing Purposes

You may receive email communications from us that inform you about your specific service, and on occasion emails that share new movies and TV shows, promote new or additional services, or contain special offers from Zip.ca and our corporate affiliates. You cannot opt out of service related emails, however you will see an opt out option at the bottom of marketing emails, which you may use to prevent receiving future emails of this nature. We may use your personal information for these purposes and may also disclose your email address and/or name to our corporate affiliates so that they can send you such information directly.

### Knowledge and Consent

Zip.ca collects personal information about you only when you voluntarily provide it. Typically, we will seek consent for the use or disclosure of your personal information at the time of collection. In certain circumstances, consent may be sought after the information has been collected but before use (for example, when we want to use information for a purpose not previously identified). The form of consent that we seek, including whether it is express or implied, will largely depend on the sensitivity of the personal information and the reasonable expectations of the individual in the circumstances.

You may withdraw consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. If you wish to withdraw your consent at any time, please contact us at privacy@zip.ca. We will inform you of the implications of withdrawing consent.

We will not, as a condition of the supply of a product or service, require you to consent to the collection, use or disclosure of information beyond that required to fulfill the explicitly specified and legitimate purposes for which the information is being provided.

## Zip.ca Services, Features and Functions

### Creating a Zip.ca Account

When you create a free Zip.ca account we require your email address and a password. Having a free Zip.ca account allows you to sign in and access services available through Zip.ca Mail. We use sign-in information to track visits to our website, to determine how many guests visit our website, to assist you should you decide to rent a movie from Zip.ca, and occasionally to inform you of service updates and special offers. This information is not disclosed to other users, members or unaffiliated third parties. 

### Rental History

We track and retain your rental history so that you can access a record of the movies and TV shows you have rented previously. This information is stored in your ZipList, under the "Rental History" tab; it is available to you alone and is not disclosed to other users, members or unaffiliated third parties.

### Billing History

We track and retain your billing history which is accessible on the "My Account" page. . This information is available to you alone and is not disclosed to other users, members or unaffiliated third parties.

### Zip.ca Ratings and Recommendations

Our website has a Rating feature where you can, at your option, rate any title in our library on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. If you rate a title in our library, we use this information to personalize the Recommendations feature of the website that is accessible to you when you Sign in. If you do not wish to receive personalized Recommendations, please do not use the Ratings feature. If you do not use the Ratings feature you will receive standard Recommendations issued by Zip.ca.

### Zip.ca Mail

When you subscribe to a Zip.ca Mail rental plan we require your Zip.ca sign-in information as well as your full name, postal address, telephone number and a valid credit card number. We use this information to process your rental requests and to ship requested DVD or Blu-ray discs to you. We request that you provide a valid credit card number during any Promotional Period in the event that discs shipped during this period are not returned and monthly charges must be incurred until all outstanding rentals are returned or charges for lost or stolen discs are assessed. If you are paying by credit card, we will use the credit card number provided by you initially for billing purposes should you continue to use Zip.ca Mail following any Promotional Period. 

We use your email address to notify you that discs in your rental list have been shipped to you, to answer inquiries that you send to us, and to communicate with you when necessary concerning billing, the administration of your account and the processing of your rental or purchase requests. As these functions are necessary to the proper administration of your Zip.ca Mail plan, we do not offer an opt-out from such email communication.

### Zip.ca Kiosk

When you rent from a Zip.ca Kiosk, we collect your credit card information to process your rental. If you provide your email address at a Zip.ca Kiosk we will use it to confirm your rental, provide you with an electronic receipt, answer inquiries that you send to us, and to communicate with you when necessary concerning billing. We may also send you special offers and news about new products or services. 

When you rent from a Zip.ca Kiosk we assign an account number to you, so that we can track and retain your rental history as well as information related to repeat visits and traffic to our Zip.ca Kiosks. This information is not disclosed to other users or unaffiliated third parties. 

## Contact Us

In the event that you have any questions about the Zip.ca Privacy Policy or if you have reason to believe that we may have failed to adhere to this Privacy Statement, send an email to [privacy@zip.ca](mailto:privacy@zip.ca) or contact our [Member Services team](http://www.zip.ca/ContactUs.aspx).
